Yumi A tvN original series
유미 tvN 오리지널 시리즈
Yumi's Cells
유미의 세포
Episode 29 Sae Yi doesn't know...
29화 세이는 모른다...
Sae Yi doesn't know number four
세이는 4번을 몰라
You should at least buy your own wine glasses.
최소한 자신만의 와인잔을 구입해야 합니다.
- Yumi. - We met in the elevator.
- 유미. - 엘리베이터에서 만났어요.
She didn't know that I moved.
그녀는 내가 이사했다는 것을 몰랐습니다.
Thank you for this.
감사합니다.
- See you later, Yumi. - Good bye.
- 나중에 봐, 유미. - 안녕히 가세요.
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Yumi, I'm planning a housewarming party. Please come.
유미 씨, 집들이를 계획 중이에요. 꼭 오세요.
Sure, invite me. I'll come.
물론이죠. 초대해 주세요. 내가 갈게.
Then, have a good time. Good night.
그럼 즐거운 시간 보내세요. 안녕히 주무세요.
Yumi.
유미.
How are you here all of a sudden? You said you were going to bed.
갑자기 여기 어떻게 오셨나요? 당신은 잠자리에 든다고 말했습니다.
Come in.
들어오세요.
Come in, Yumi.
들어오세요, 유미님.
Yumi.
유미.
Seo Sae Yi said she moved here.
서세이가 여기로 이사 왔다고 하더군요.
Ah, that? I guessed she moved in since we were doing a lot of overtime work these days
아, 그거요? 요즘 야근을 많이 해서 이사 온 줄 알았어요
and it was hard to commute. I didn't know either.
그리고 출퇴근도 힘들었다. 나도 몰랐다.
You didn't know but she comes to borrow a wine glass at this time?
몰랐는데 이 시간에 와인잔을 빌리러 온 걸까요?
I found out later.
나중에 알았습니다.
- When? - A few days after she moved in.
- 언제? - 이사 온 지 며칠 후.
She said she moved in last month.
지난달에 이사했다고 하더군요.
So, you didn't tell me until now? While you knew all along?
그럼 지금까지 나한테 말 안 했어? 그동안 알고 계셨나요?
I forgot. I guess I forgot.
잊어버렸어요. 잊어버린 것 같아요.
It's not like Sae Yi moving in is something important.
세이가 이사오는 게 중요한 게 아니거든요.
Come in for now. It's nice to see you all of a sudden.
지금은 들어오세요. 갑자기 만나서 반가워요.
Don't try to let this pass again. You said you forgot?
이 일이 다시 지나가도록 놔두지 마세요. 잊어버렸다고 했죠?
Don't talk nonsense.
말도 안되는 소리를하지 마십시오.
Last week, I asked you to meet me at your house and you said you'd meet me outside, right?
지난주에 집에서 만나자고 했더니 밖에서 보자고 하더군요?
You were afraid that I'd bump into her because she was here. Isn't it? It was like that the week before, too.
당신은 그녀가 여기 있기 때문에 내가 그녀와 부딪힐까 봐 두려워했습니다. 그렇지 않나요? 지난주에도 그랬어요.
I was nearby and said I was going to go up for a bit and you came out instead saying that I didn't need to.
근처에 있다가 잠깐 올라간다고 했더니, 그럴 필요 없다고 대신 나오셨어요.
But still, you forgot? You deceived me on purpose!
그런데 아직도 잊으셨나요? 당신은 고의로 나를 속였습니다!
- I didn't deceive— - You did! Why are you lying?
- 난 속이지 않았어— - 그랬어요! 왜 거짓말을 하는 거야?
Because I thought you would be like this.
당신이 이럴 거라고 생각했거든요.
- What? - You've always been sensitive when it comes to Sae Yi.
- 무엇? - 세이에 관해서는 늘 예민한 편이셨어요.
I didn't say it because it bothered me, too. I was afraid it would come out like this.
나도 그게 귀찮아서 말하지 않았어. 이렇게 나올까봐 두려웠어요.
I never told her to move in here. And, I don't have the right to tell her not to either. That's up to Sae Yi.
나는 그녀에게 여기로 이사하라고 말한 적이 없습니다. 그리고 나 역시 그녀에게 하지 말라고 말할 권리가 없습니다. 그건 Sae Yi에게 달렸습니다.
I can't kick her out.
나는 그녀를 쫓아낼 수 없습니다.
I knew you would be sensitive.
나는 당신이 예민할 것이라는 것을 알고 있었습니다.
Did he just say sensitive? That it was because Yumi is sensitive? This is really...
방금 민감하다고 했나? 유미가 예민해서 그랬던 걸까요? 이건 정말...
This is really disgraceful. I can't stand this either!
이것은 정말 수치스러운 일입니다. 나도 이건 참을 수 없어!
Let's curse him out. Guys, bring the curse bomb!
그를 저주하자. 얘들아, 저주폭탄을 가져와!
No, we have to get him and torture him with facts.
아니, 사실을 가지고 그를 잡아서 고문해야 합니다.
What... torture?
뭐... 고문?
We need Yumi's great encyclopedia.
유미의 훌륭한 백과사전이 필요해요.
In a case like this, nothing is left out and recorded.
이런 경우에는 아무것도 남지 않고 기록됩니다.
- Copy it and give it to everyone. - Understood!
- 복사해서 모두에게 나눠주세요. - 이해했다!
- Just extract the parts about Wung and Sae Yi. - All right!
- Wung과 Sae Yi에 관한 부분만 추출해 보세요. - 괜찮은!
It's not because Yumi is sensitive.
유미가 예민해서가 아니다.
- We have to prove it. - Found it! Sae Yi's strange behavior.
- 증명해야 해요. - 찾았어요! 세이의 이상한 행동.
On July the 21th, the yuja syrup incident!
7월 21일 유자시럽 사건!
You didn't make it yourself, right?
당신이 직접 만든 건 아니죠?
Oh, this?
아, 이거요?
- Someone gave it to me. - Wung lied. And eventually, we confirmed that Sae Yi gave it to him.
- 누군가 나한테 줬어요. - 웅이 거짓말을 했어요. 그리고 결국 세이가 준 것으로 확인됐습니다.
We have some yuja syrup here, too. The one I made.
여기 유자 시럽도 있어요. 내가 만든 것.
I found something too! There was also the bombing incident on social media, on August the 6th.
나도 뭔가를 찾았어! 지난 8월 6일에는 소셜미디어에서도 폭탄테러 사건이 발생했다.
- That's right! That! -We're working overtime again. Three Eagles, bravely working.
- 좋아요! 저것! - 또 야근을 하게 됐어요. 용감하게 일하는 세 독수리.
What the...? Why is she posting this picture on her own account?
무슨...? 그녀는 왜 자신의 계정에 이 사진을 올리는 걸까요?
It's weird, right?
이상해요, 그렇죠?
Yes, the intention is impure. Why did she post it, even though she knows he has a girlfriend?
예, 의도가 불순합니다. 여자친구 있는 걸 알면서 왜 글을 올렸을까?
- What's her name? - Seo Sae Yi.
- 이름이 뭐예요? - 서세이.
Even her name is strange, the way she's acting is strange. She is strange.
이름도 이상하고, 연기하는 방식도 이상해요. 그녀는 이상하다.
Is there anything else?
다른 것이 있나요?
Another one! Pretending to know Wung's tastes in everything.
또 하나! 모든 것에서 Wung의 취향을 아는 척합니다.
You don't like dongdongju?
동동주 안 좋아해요?
- Well, it's not that I don't like it— - Dongdongju is Wung's favorite.
- 뭐, 싫다는 건 아니고- - 동동주는 웅이가 가장 좋아하는 것이에요.
Wung doesn't really like yubuchobap. He's more of a kimbap guy.
웅 씨는 유부초밥을 별로 안 좋아해요. 그 사람은 오히려 김밥을 좋아하는 사람이에요.
I think Yumi's birthday was the cherry on the cake.
내 생각엔 유미의 생일은 케이크 위의 체리였던 것 같아.
That necklace. We picked it out together.
그 목걸이. 우리는 그것을 함께 골랐습니다.
He said it was your birthday. He kept picking weird things, so I picked that for him.
그 사람이 오늘이 네 생일이라고 하더군요. 그 사람이 계속 이상한 걸 골라서 내가 그걸 골라줬어요.
It looks good on you.
잘 어울리네요.
The yuja syrup. You lied about that at first.
유자시럽. 당신은 처음에 그것에 대해 거짓말을 했어요.
And also made a quick excuse.
그리고 빠른 변명도 했습니다.
What about Seo Sae Yi?
서세이는요?
Whenever I see her, she pretends to know all your tastes and tell me about them every time.
내가 그녀를 볼 때마다 그녀는 당신의 취향을 모두 아는 척하고 매번 그것에 대해 나에게 이야기합니다.
She posted a couple picture on her social media without any permission,
그녀는 허락 없이 자신의 소셜 미디어에 커플 사진을 게시했습니다.
and just as if it wasn't enough to pretend to be your girlfriend now...
그리고 마치 지금 여자친구인 척 하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않은 것처럼...
she even moved downstairs.
심지어 아래층으로 이사하기도 했어요.
She comes to your home at this time under the pretext of borrowing things.
그녀는 이때 물건을 빌린다는 구실로 당신의 집에 찾아옵니다.
And it doesn't look like it's the first time you two exchanged things.
그리고 너희 둘이 물건을 교환한 게 이번이 처음은 아닌 것 같은데.
You said that I am sensitive? No.
내가 예민하다고 했지? 아니요.
This is absurd, Wung.
이건 터무니없는 일이야, 웡.
Anyone will say it's strange, if you ask them.
누가 물어보면 이상하다고 할 겁니다.
Don't you think so?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
About that...
그것에 대해...
She has always been like that.
그녀는 항상 그랬습니다.
- She has always been like that? - There's nothing I can do about it. Her personality is normally like that. Doing whatever she wants.
- 항상 그랬어요? - 내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어요. 성격은 원래 그런 편이에요. 그녀가 원하는 것은 무엇이든 합니다.
- That's why— - I'm supposed to move on because she's that kind of person?
- 그래서— - 그 사람이 그런 사람이니까 내가 넘어가야 하는 건가요?
Because she's your friend? Because she has always been like that?
그 사람이 네 친구라서? 그녀는 항상 그랬기 때문에?
That's not right.
그건 옳지 않아요.
You have a girlfriend now. You have me!
당신은 이제 여자 친구가 있습니다. 당신은 나를 가지고 있습니다!
It's different from before!
예전과는 다르다!
Then you have to cut it off. You could have cut it off.
그러면 끊어야 합니다. 잘라낼 수도 있었습니다.
But you didn't and kept lying to me.
그런데 당신은 그러지 않고 나에게 계속 거짓말을 했어요.
Yumi...
유미...
Emergency. Emergency. Yumi is burning with anger.
비상. 비상. 유미는 분노에 불타오르고 있다.
I've never seen Yumi this angry. What should we do?
유미가 이렇게 화내는 걸 본 적이 없어요. 우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
But what did Wung do so wrong?
그런데 Wung은 무엇을 그렇게 잘못 했습니까?
- What? - We've been doing our best.
- 무엇? - 우리는 최선을 다해 왔습니다.
Whenever it got difficult, we turned into Bear mode every time.
어려울 때마다 매번 베어 모드로 돌입했어요.
You should have told me earlier
좀 더 일찍 나한테 말했어야 했는데
We did everything.
우리는 모든 것을 했습니다.
We even tried to stop her from moving here.
우리는 그녀가 여기로 이사하는 것을 막으려고까지 했습니다.
Ah, Wung. I've been visiting homes when you were on vacation.
아, 웅. 나는 당신이 휴가를 갔을 때 집을 방문했습니다.
Homes? You're going to move? - Yes.
주택? 이사 갈 건가요? - 예.
The taxi fare is getting too high, I can't keep doing it.
택시비가 너무 비싸서 계속 할 수가 없어요.
- It's better to move near the office. - That's more convenient.
- 사무실 근처로 이사하는 것이 좋습니다. - 그게 더 편해요.
The officetel where you're living is nice. The location too.
당신이 살고 있는 오피스텔은 좋아요. 위치도요.
- Where I'm currently living? - Yes.
- 현재 내가 살고 있는 곳은 어디입니까? - 예.
It was the best place nearby.
근처에서 가장 좋은 곳이었습니다.
It's too expensive there. It's all overpriced. It's facing north, so there is little sunlight.
거긴 너무 비싸요. 가격이 다 비싸요. 북쪽을 향하고 있어 햇빛이 거의 들지 않습니다.
The water pressure is too weak. The poop won't go down.
수압이 너무 약해요. 똥이 내려가지 않습니다.
Poop, unclog, poop, unclog. Do you want to live like this? You can't.
똥, 막힘 해제, 똥, 막힘 해제. 이렇게 살고 싶나요? 당신은 할 수 없습니다.
You're saying your toilet's water pressure is weak? At your place?
화장실 수압이 약하다는 말씀이신가요? 당신 집에?
It's not. His toilet flush is like a waterfall, really.
그렇지 않습니다. 그의 화장실 수세식은 정말 폭포와 같습니다.
This place's water pressure is great.
이곳 수압이 엄청나네요.
But what can we do about her moving however she wants?
하지만 그녀가 원하는 대로 이사하게 하려면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
That's right. We've never been distracted in front of Sae Yi. This is a bit unfair.
좋아요. 우리는 Sae Yi 앞에서 주의가 산만해진 적이 없습니다. 이건 좀 불공평해요.
Let's explain this well to Yumi so that she understands.
유미가 이해할 수 있도록 잘 설명해보자.
Let's run the algorithm!
알고리즘을 실행해 보자!
Wung's algorithm is running starting from now, .
Wung의 알고리즘은 지금부터 실행됩니다.
Yumi, first let's sit down and hear me out—
유미야, 먼저 앉아서 내 말을 들어보자—
Sae Yi is actually acting like your girlfriend pretending to be your friend.
세이는 사실 여자친구인 척 친구인 척 행동하고 있어요.
But why are you accepting it all?
그런데 왜 그걸 다 받아들이는 거죠?
- I've never accept— - You are right now!
- 난 한 번도 동의한 적 없어— - 당신은 바로 지금입니다!
You said I have a sensitive personality, right? That's not it. You're the one who isn't careful.
제가 예민한 성격이라고 하셨죠? 그게 아닙니다. 당신은 조심하지 않는 사람입니다.
Neither Sae Yi nor you are careful,
Sae Yi도 당신도 조심하지 않아요,
and you don't have the least consideration toward me.
그리고 당신은 나에 대해 최소한의 배려도 없습니다.
Next step, relieving Yumi's ang—
다음 단계는 유미의 괴로움을 해소하는 것—
Yumi's ang— Yumi's ang—
유미 앙— 유미 앙—
Yumi's— What's going on? What's happening?
유미의— 무슨 일이야? 무슨 일이야?
Look at that!
저것 좀 봐!
- What is this? - This can't be!
- 이게 뭔가요? - 그럴 리가 없어!
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
We're in trouble. The Ice Gu Wung state has been activated!
우리는 곤경에 빠졌습니다. 아이스 구웅 상태가 활성화되었습니다!
When Wung gets angry, everything freezes!
Wung이 화를 내면 모든 것이 얼어붙습니다!
Am I wrong?
내가 틀렸나요?
I was taking care of it in a way that wouldn't make everyone uncomfortable.
모두가 불편하지 않도록 배려했습니다.
Does keeping it a secret from me take care of it?
나한테 비밀로 하면 알아서 처리되나요?
Sae Yi is just a friend to me.
세이는 나에게 그저 친구일 뿐이다.
Isn't that all that matters?
그게 전부가 아니지 않나요?
That's not my point right now.
지금은 그게 내 요점이 아니다.
Why do I have to explain every single time? That's she's just a friend.
왜 매번 설명을 해야 하죠? 그 사람은 그냥 친구일 뿐이에요.
What is that? Is he getting mad right now?
저게 뭐에요? 그 사람 지금 화났나요?
Isn't he the one who did something wrong? He should be begging on his knees!
그 사람이 잘못한 게 아닌가요? 그는 무릎을 꿇고 구걸해야 합니다!
How dare he be mad at us?
그 사람이 어떻게 감히 우리에게 화를 내는 걸까요?
Shouldn't you be apologizing rather than explaining?
해명보다는 사과를 해야 하는 것 아닌가요?
I have nothing to apologize for.
저는 사과할 것이 없습니다.
You have nothing to apologize for?
사과할 일 없나요?
I don't.
나는 아니에요.
I'm so mad at you.
너한테 너무 화가 났어.
But you have nothing to apologize for?
그런데 사과할 게 없나요?
Fine, I got it.
알겠습니다. 알겠습니다.
I'll leave.
나는 떠날 것이다.
♫ I want to smile for you ♫
♫ 나는 당신을 위해 웃고 싶어요 ♫
Wait! Is it right to leave?
기다리다! 떠나는 것이 맞나요?
We didn't solve anything.
우리는 아무것도 해결하지 못했습니다.
♫ If you meet my eyes first ♫
♫ 먼저 눈이 마주치면 ♫
Yumi left. She just left!
유미가 떠났다. 그녀는 방금 떠났어요!
No! Stop her!
아니요! 그만둬!
Like an awkward confession
어색한 고백처럼
♫ I want to be comforted ♫
♫ 위로받고 싶어 ♫
Is he stopping her? No way. He is, right?
그가 그녀를 막고 있나요? 안 돼요. 그 사람 맞죠?
No. Yumi left. We should do something!
아니요. 유미가 떠났어요. 뭔가 해야 해!
This is not right. Every function is frozen!
이것은 옳지 않습니다. 모든 기능이 정지되었습니다!
♫ I want to smile for you ♫
♫ 나는 당신을 위해 웃고 싶어요 ♫
♫ I want our eyes to meet again ♫
♫ 우리 눈이 다시 마주쳤으면 좋겠어 ♫
♫ Today again, after a long time ♫
♫ 오늘도 오랜만에, ♫
Stop her. Please!
그녀를 멈춰라. 제발!
♫ It finally returned ♫
♫ 드디어 돌아왔어 ♫
♫ Finally it returned. ♫
♫ 마침내 그것이 돌아왔습니다. ♫
♫ I want to hang onto you ♫
♫ 나는 당신에게 매달리고 싶어요 ♫
♫ Before we get further apart ♫
♫ 우리가 더 멀어지기 전에 ♫
♫ On top of my pillow ♫
♫ 내 베개 위에 ♫
♫ our beautiful times ♫
♫ 우리의 아름다운 시절 ♫
♫ keep falling. ♫
♫ 계속 넘어져요. ♫
How can he do this?
그는 어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있습니까?
How can Wung do this?
Wung은 어떻게 이것을 할 수 있습니까?
I thought he'd hold onto us and apologize.
나는 그가 우리를 붙잡고 사과할 것이라고 생각했습니다.
I've never seen him so cold. I was a little scared.
나는 그가 그렇게 차가운 것을 본 적이 없습니다. 나는 조금 무서웠다.
He'll probably call, right? If he does, let's forgive him for now.
그 사람이 아마 전화할 거예요, 그렇죠? 만약 그렇다면 지금은 그를 용서하자.
And we can make him promise not to let this ever happen again.
그리고 우리는 그에게 이런 일이 다시는 일어나지 않도록 약속하게 할 수 있습니다.
Yes, let's do that.
예, 그렇게 합시다.
Missed call - Mom
부재중 전화 - 엄마
Hello? Mom, you called.
안녕하세요? 엄마, 전화했어요.
Yes, I'm on my way back.
네, 돌아가는 중이에요.
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
He's not even calling. Isn't he even worried if she made it home safely?
그 사람은 전화도 안 해요. 그녀가 무사히 집에 돌아갈 수 있을지 걱정도 되지 않을까요?
He'll at least text, right? No way he wouldn't.
최소한 문자라도 할 거에요, 그렇죠? 절대로 그는 그렇지 않을 것입니다.
Wake up!
깨우다!
Until this morning, there was no text or call.
오늘 아침까지 문자도 전화도 없었습니다.
This has happened for the first time ever since we started dating Wung.
우리가 Wung과 데이트를 시작한 이후 처음으로 이런 일이 일어났습니다.
Therefore, I think everyone should acknowledge this is a very serious situation.
그러므로 이번 사태는 매우 심각한 상황임을 모두가 인정해야 한다고 생각합니다.
Then I'll set the breakup alarm as of 11 o'clock last night.
그럼 어젯밤 11시에 이별 알람을 맞춰 놓겠습니다.
- Breakup alarm? - What's that?
- 이별 알람? - 그게 뭐죠?
It's a new machine. Breakup alarm.
그것은 새로운 기계입니다. 이별 알람.
Usage manual.
사용설명서.
If there is no contact for 24 hours after the fight, it will be considered a breakup.
싸운 후 24시간 동안 연락이 없으면 이별으로 간주됩니다.
Hold on! 24 hours is too short! Can we make it 36 hours?
기다리다! 24시간은 너무 짧다! 36시간 동안 할 수 있을까요?
She's right. When you date, it's possible to fight.
그녀 말이 맞아요. 데이트를 하다 보면 싸울 수도 있다.
How about we make it 48 hours so it's easy to calculate?
계산하기 쉽도록 48시간으로 만드는 것은 어떨까요?
Yeah, let's make it 48 hours.
응, 48시간으로 하자.
48 hours is good.
48시간이 좋다.
- We can't. - Why not?
- 그럴 수 없어요. - 왜 안 돼?
We can only set it up to 24 hours by default.
기본적으로 최대 24시간까지만 설정할 수 있습니다.
Since we left Wung's place at 11:11pm last night...
어젯밤 11시 11분에 Wung의 집을 떠난 이후로...
- Eonni. - Yes? - I've made the report.
-언니. - 예? - 보고서를 작성했어요.
- Thank you. - Please check it over.
- 감사합니다. - 확인해 보시기 바랍니다.
All right.
괜찮은.
- Yumi, good morning. - Good morning.
- 유미 씨, 좋은 아침이에요. - 좋은 아침이에요.
Yeah.
응.
- Hello. - Good morning.
- 안녕하세요. - 좋은 아침이에요.
If, until 11:11 tonight,
만약, 오늘 밤 11시 11분까지
we don't hear from Wung, this relationship is over.
Wung의 소식이 없습니다. 이 관계는 끝났습니다.
- Good morning. - Hey.
- 좋은 아침이에요. - 여기요.
You're all early. You must be tired.
다들 일찍 오셨군요. 피곤하겠네요.
Hey, you call 11 early?
야, 11시에 일찍 전화했어?
What's this? Coffee?
이건 뭐죠? 커피?
Yes, I got some coffee.
네, 커피를 좀 샀어요.
Ice latte for you, right?
아이스 라떼는 당신을 위한 것 맞죠?
Wow, I'm so thankful. I was feeling lazy to go out to get some milk—
와, 정말 고마워요. 우유 사러 나가기 귀찮아서—
I knew it. You're the best.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다. 당신은 최고입니다.
Iced Americano for Wung.
Wung을 위한 아이스 아메리카노.
Wung, have some coffee.
웅, 커피 좀 마셔요.
- Are you all right? - What do you mean?
- 괜찮아요? - 무슨 뜻이에요?
I mean ... I was just worried.
그러니까... 그냥 걱정이 됐어요.
We ran into each other at the apartment yesterday and Yumi seemed flustered.
어제 아파트에서 우연히 마주쳤는데 유미가 당황한 것 같았어요.
I didn't know you didn't tell her.
당신이 그녀에게 말하지 않은 줄은 몰랐어요.
- Is it still not working? - It's totally messed up. Nothing works.
- 아직도 작동이 안 되나요? - 완전히 엉망이 됐어요. 아무것도 작동하지 않습니다.
- What's that? - Huh?
- 그게 뭐죠? - 뭐?
What is that? I didn't press that.
저게 뭐에요? 나는 그것을 누르지 않았습니다.
I know about Wung very well.
나는 Wung에 대해 아주 잘 알고 있습니다.
Isn't that Sae Yi's voice?
그거 세이 목소리 아니야?
I know Wung very well. So from now on, I will take him over.
나는 Wung을 아주 잘 알고 있습니다. 그러니 이제부터 내가 그 사람을 맡겠습니다.
- It's a virus! - What?
- 바이러스예요! - 무엇?
A Sae Yi Virus infiltrated through the broken circuits!
부서진 회로를 통해 새이 바이러스가 침투했다!
Should I tell you what kind of a person Wung is?
웅이가 어떤 사람인지 말해줄까?
You didn't have a fight with Yumi by chance, right?
우연히 유미랑 싸운 건 아니겠죠?
Omo! Did you really fight?
오모! 정말 싸웠나요?
Number one, Gu Wung can't hide his feelings.
첫째, 구웅은 자신의 감정을 숨길 수 없습니다.
W-where's my coffee?
여- 내 커피는 어디 있지?
I put it over there.
나는 그것을 거기에 두었습니다.
Coffee's the best after a good poop.
똥을 싸고 난 뒤에는 커피가 최고죠.
Enjoy.
즐기다.
So his face shows all the information.
그래서 그의 얼굴은 모든 정보를 보여줍니다.
I should have made a stronger password for the gate of his heart, like Yumi.
유미처럼 마음의 문에 더 강력한 비밀번호를 만들어 줬어야 했는데.
The security system must have been too lax.
보안 시스템이 너무 허술했나봐요.
And for Wung, himself is always his top priority.
그리고 Wung에게는 항상 자신이 최우선입니다.
Top 10 priorities: #3 Mother #2 Yumi #1 Gu Wung
상위 10가지 우선순위: #3 어머니 #2 유미 1위 구웅
Then whose side would he take if #1 and #2 fights?
그렇다면 1번과 2번이 싸우면 누구 편을 들 것인가?
Yes, Seonbae.
응, 선배.
Yes, yes. Pardon?
예, 그렇습니다. 뭐라고요?
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
Now, should we make #1 push #2 out?
이제 #1이 #2를 밀어내도록 해야 할까요?
I don't want to get involved in people's dating lives, and I'm careful before saying anything.
저는 사람들의 연애생활에 끼어들고 싶지 않고, 말을 하기 전에는 조심스럽습니다.
I don't really know your situation as a couple,
나는 당신의 커플 상황을 잘 모르겠습니다
so it's not easy to say, but I don't want you to be too stressed.
그러니 쉽게 말씀드리기는 어렵지만 너무 스트레스 받지 않으셨으면 좋겠습니다.
I'm worried that you're not happy dating, that you're just getting stressed out.
연애가 행복하지 않은 것, 스트레스만 받는 것은 아닌지 걱정됩니다.
No matter what anyone says, the most important is yourself.
누가 뭐래도 가장 중요한 것은 자기 자신입니다.
Don't you think?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
You're right. I think so, too.
당신 말이 맞아요. 나도 그렇게 생각해요.
You get close because you can understand.
이해할 수 있기 때문에 가까이 다가가는 것입니다.
But I don't think you should be understanding and condone everything just because you're close with that person.
하지만 그 사람과 친하다고 해서 모든 걸 이해하고 용납할 필요는 없을 것 같아요.
No, no. Wung, get back to your senses! You shouldn't be fooled by a virus!
아니, 아니. 웅, 정신 차려! 바이러스에 속으면 안 됩니다!
You're right. If you don't match with someone, trying to force it to work out is only going to give you stress.
당신 말이 맞아요. 어울리지 않는 사람에게 억지로 해결하려고 하면 스트레스만 받을 뿐입니다.
No matter how good it is or how much you've grown attached,
아무리 좋든, 얼마나 애착을 ​​가지든
when people don't fit each other, you'll forever not fit each other.
사람들이 서로 맞지 않으면 영원히 서로 맞지 않을 것입니다.
I think so, too.
나도 그렇게 생각해요.
So you aren't going to make up with Miss Yumi?
그럼 유미 씨와 화해하지 않을 건가요?
- What do you mean? - Hmm?
- 무슨 뜻이에요? - 흠?
I'm talking about you right now.
나는 지금 당신에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
Your actions make me uncomfortable.
당신의 행동은 나를 불편하게 만듭니다.
I think there is a limit to me understanding everything because you're close.
친하기 때문에 다 이해하기에는 한계가 있는 것 같아요.
Your actions are stressing me out right now.
당신의 행동이 지금 나에게 스트레스를 주고 있어요.
My actions? What did I do?
내 행동은? 내가 무엇을 했나요?
Is it because I moved to your apartment building?
내가 당신 아파트로 이사했기 때문인가요?
You guys fought because of that and now you're taking it out on me?
너희들 그거 때문에 싸웠는데 이제 나한테까지 뺏어가는 거야?
I can't believe it. I mean what am I supposed to do when work is close by?
믿을 수가 없어요. 내 말은, 직장이 근처에 있으면 뭘 해야 한다는 거야?
Do I have to consider those type of things between friends?
친구사이에도 그런 것들을 고려해야 하나요?
Is that really your point of view?
그게 정말 당신의 관점인가요?
And not Yumi's point of view?
그리고 유미의 관점은 아닌가요?
Are you talking as my friend or Yumi's boyfriend?
내 친구라고 하는 거야, 아니면 유미의 남자 친구라고 하는 거야?
Gu Wung, aren't we friends?
구웅씨, 우리 친구 아닌가요?
Longer than your dating relationship at least?
적어도 데이트 관계보다 오래 걸리나요?
Number three, word 'friend' is a weak spot for Gu Wung.
세 번째, '친구'라는 단어는 구웅에게 약점이다.
Argh! This won't do.
아아! 이건 안 돼요.
I haven't changed a bit. It's you who's changed.
나는 조금도 변하지 않았습니다. 변한 건 바로 당신이에요.
I'm the one that should be hurt.
상처받아야 할 사람은 바로 나다.
You did change ever since you started dating Yumi.
유미와 사귄 이후로 당신은 정말 변했어요.
People tend to get similar when they date for a long time and I'm worried that might happen to you, too.
사람들은 연애를 오래 하다 보면 닮아가는 경향이 있는데 당신도 그런 일이 생길까 걱정이 된다.
Like someone. All twisted.
누군가처럼. 모두 뒤틀려 있습니다.
Transmitting to all cells! #2 is being attacked currently!
모든 세포에 전송 중! #2가 현재 공격받고 있습니다!
All Wung's cells, wake up!
웅의 모든 세포들이여, 일어나라!
Sae Yi knows Wung very well, but she doesn't know the fourth principle, yet.
Sae Yi는 Wung을 매우 잘 알고 있지만 아직 네 번째 원칙을 알지 못합니다.
I 💝Yumi
나 💝유미
When you look with a twisted view, even friendship can look weird.
삐뚤어진 시선으로 보면 우정조차 이상하게 보일 수 있다.
Hey, Seo Sae Yi.
안녕하세요, 서세이님.
Watch what you say.
당신이 말하는 것을 조심하세요.
Episode 25 : Hidden Card
25화 : 히든카드
Daehan Noodles
대한국수
Eonni, summary of Dongseo Corporation.
언니, 동서코퍼레이션 개요.
Eonni, are you not feeling well?
언니 몸 안 좋아?
No.
아니요.
Yumi, cheer up.
유미 씨, 힘내세요.
It's only five o'clock.
이제 겨우 5시입니다.
But a great flood started.
그러나 큰 홍수가 시작되었습니다.
No, not yet!
아니요, 아직은 아닙니다!
Yumi, it's not 11 yet.
유미 씨, 아직 11시가 아니에요.
Why are you like this already?
벌써 왜 이러는 걸까요?
No!
아니요!
Just like one human can't stop natural disasters,
한 사람이 자연재해를 막을 수 없는 것처럼,
one cell cannot stop the emotions rushing in.
하나의 세포도 밀려드는 감정을 막을 수 없습니다.
In the end, the flood engulfed the village.
결국 홍수가 마을을 휩쓸었습니다.
Wung never contacted me.
Wung은 나에게 연락하지 않았습니다.
Not even once.
한 번도 아닙니다.
- Good morning! - Hello. [That winter]
- 좋은 아침이에요! - 안녕하세요. [그해 겨울]
- Yumi, good morning. - Good morning.
- 유미 씨, 좋은 아침이에요. - 좋은 아침이에요.
I thought he'd send me at least one text after a while. [Next Summer]
나는 그가 잠시 후에 나에게 적어도 한 통의 문자를 보낼 것이라고 생각했습니다. [다음 여름]
But he didn't.
그러나 그는 그렇지 않았습니다.
- Hey! - Where do you get these things from anyway?
- 여기요! - 그런데 이런 것들은 어디서 구하나요?
I didn't contact him either.
나 역시 그 사람에게 연락하지 않았다.
Since it wasn't my fault, back then,
내 잘못이 아니었으니까 그때는
I thought I shouldn't be the one contacting him first.
그 사람한테 먼저 연락하면 안 될 것 같았거든요.
Winter again
다시 겨울
One day after four years, this suddenly came to my mind.
4년이 지난 어느 날 문득 이런 생각이 들었습니다.
What if something happened to Wung that day?
그날 Wung에게 무슨 일이 생기면 어떻게 될까요?
I searched for his blog or social media, just in case.
혹시나 해서 그의 블로그나 SNS를 찾아봤습니다.
And I ended up finding it.
그리고 결국 찾았어요.
How was he doing?
그는 어떻게 지내고 있었나요?
He was doing well.
그는 잘 지내고 있었습니다.
Five years later.
5년 후.
The end. I talked too much about me.
끝. 나는 나에 대해 너무 많이 이야기했습니다.
Awesome. I didn't know you had such a love story!
엄청난. 당신에게 그런 사랑 이야기가 있는 줄은 몰랐어요!
It's just a common story.
그냥 흔한 이야기입니다.
But don't you think things would've been different if you had called first back then?
그런데 그때 먼저 전화를 했다면 상황이 달라졌을 것 같지 않나요?
Do you think so?
그렇게 생각하시나요?
If you were to go back to then, do you think you'd contact him?
그때로 돌아가면 그 사람한테 연락할 것 같나요?
Probably?
아마?
Section Chief!
과장님!
Then I will time warp you to five years ago, so you should go contact him.
그럼 5년 전으로 타임워프할 테니 가서 연락해 보세요.
Goodness. Did you just wake up?
선량. 방금 일어났어요?
It's so sad. Why did they break up?
너무 슬프다. 그들은 왜 헤어졌나요?
Sure, thanks for the thought.
물론이죠. 생각해 주셔서 감사합니다.
You should time travel and ask him to date you again.
시간여행을 해서 그에게 다시 데이트하자고 요청해야 합니다.
What?
무엇?
What was that just now?
방금 그거 뭐였지?
That skill was 'You're writing a scenario'!
그 스킬은 바로 '시나리오를 쓰고 있다'였습니다!
- Huh? - How did that happen?
- 뭐? - 어떻게 된 거죠?
That's Writer's skill.
그게 작가의 능력이다.
Writer is dead.
작가는 죽었습니다.
I resurrected her!
내가 그녀를 부활시켰어요!
It's been a while since I wrote a scenario.
오랜만에 시나리오를 썼습니다.
Good job, Writer.
잘했어요, 작가님.
Thanks for resurrecting me.
나를 부활시켜주셔서 감사합니다.
I'm the one who should be thankful. Thanks to your scenario, cells' minds were changed.
감사해야 할 사람은 바로 나다. 당신의 시나리오 덕분에 세포의 마음이 바뀌었습니다.
When you imagine the future, you can know what conclusion to form in the present.
미래를 상상해 보면 현재 어떤 결론이 나올지 알 수 있다.
What Yumi really wants becomes clear.
유미가 정말로 원하는 것이 무엇인지 명확해진다.
Yumi's cells, everyone assemble!
유미의 세포들 모두 모여라!
Yumi's rules come before dating rules!
연애의 규칙보다 유미의 규칙이 먼저다!
Let's go to Gu Wung.
구웅에게 가자.
Yes!
예!
I'm late. I'll get going.
나는 늦었다. 나는 갈 것이다.
See you tomorrow.
내일 봐요.
Wung.
웅.
Earlier in the morning, I think said something I shouldn't have.
아침 일찍, 해서는 안 될 말을 한 것 같아요.
It wasn't to make you mad but it seems like you're being misunderstood.
화나게 하려는 건 아니었는데 오해를 받고 있는 것 같네요.
It made me upset, so I just said it without knowing.
그게 속상해서 나도 모르게 그냥 말을 하게 됐어요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
It's fine. Let's not talk about it anymore.
괜찮습니다. 더 이상 그것에 대해 이야기하지 말자.
No, I really think what I said earlier was a mistake.
아니, 아까 말한 건 정말 실수였다고 생각해요.
I'm sorry. I'll be careful from now on.
죄송합니다. 이제부터 조심하겠습니다.
I think I was a bit harsh too. Forget about it.
저도 좀 심했던 것 같아요. 잊어버리세요.
No, no. You said what you had to.
아니, 아니. 당신은 당신이해야 할 일을 말했습니다.
You want to eat pajeon before you go? I'm hungry.
가기 전에 파전 먹고 갈래? 배고파요.
Let's eat next time.
다음에 먹자.
You're leaving now?
지금 떠나는 건가요?
Yeah, I think I need to leave early today.
응, 오늘은 일찍 나가야 할 것 같아.
No, if he's leaving now that means he's going to Yumi.
아니, 지금 떠난다면 유미에게 간다는 뜻이다.
Then it's back to square one.
그런 다음 다시 원점으로 돌아갑니다.
We can't go back to square one.
우리는 원점으로 돌아갈 수 없습니다.
I'm leaving first. I'll see you tomorrow.
나 먼저 갈게. 내일 뵙겠습니다.
Wung.
웅.
What?
무엇?
Wung, we used to have a very special relationship.
웅, 우리는 아주 특별한 관계를 갖고 있었어요.
If I get married it'll be Gu Wung, right?
결혼하면 구웅이겠죠?
If I get married, it's going to be Gu Wung.
제가 결혼하면 구웅이 될 거예요.
I have something to say, Wung.
할 말이 있어요, 웅.
I—
나—
I thought you were friends.
나는 당신이 친구라고 생각했습니다.
- Yumi, how— - Wait.
- 유미 씨, 어떻게— - 잠깐만요.
I need to talk to Sae Yi first.
먼저 Sae Yi와 얘기를 해야 해요.
You said you were friends, so what are you doing right now?
친구라고 했는데 지금 뭐하고 있어요?
- You said you were just friends. - Yes.
- 그냥 친구라고 했잖아요. - 예.
But, Yumi, according to you, friends can't even hold hands—
그런데 유미 씨 말에 따르면 친구는 손도 못 잡는다고—
No, they can't.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다.
- Then I— - Yes, don't.
- 그럼 난- - 응, 그러지 마.
- What did I— - Don't do anything.
- 내가 뭘- - 아무것도 하지 마세요.
- Well, you— - No, I don't understand, so don't do it.
- 글쎄, 당신은- - 아니, 이해가 안 되니까 하지 마세요.
Wait!
기다리다!
You won't even let me get a word in.
내가 한 마디도 말하게 놔두지 않을 거예요.
- What did I even do that you keep telling me I can't– - All your actions up until this point.
- 내가 무슨 짓을 했기에 당신은 나한테 계속 못한다고 하는 걸까요? - 지금까지의 모든 행동.
Don't do those things again from now on.
이제부터 다시는 그런 일을 하지 마세요.
My actions? What did I do?
내 행동은? 내가 무엇을 했나요?
I don't have any idea what you're saying right now. I don't.
지금 무슨 말씀을 하시는지 전혀 모르겠습니다. 나는 아니에요.
- Don't you know? - No, I don't.
- 모르시나요? - 아니, 그렇지 않아요.
- Stop it. - There's no way you don't know.
- 그만해요. - 모르실 리가 없어요.
No, I really don't know at all.
아니요, 전혀 모르겠습니다.
Your Respectful Honor, since she keeps insisting she doesn't know, let's make sure she knows.
존경하는 재판장님, 계속해서 모른다고 하니 꼭 알고 있도록 합시다.
Listen up, Seo Sae Yi, as of now I'm going to make my judgment.
잘 들어라 서세이 이제 판단은 내가 할게.
I heard you have a cold. Make this at home for breakfast and dinner.
감기에 걸렸다고 들었어요. 아침 저녁으로 집에서 만들어 보세요.
Gifting yuja tea syrup and writing a memo that could confuse a guy.
유자청을 선물하고 남자를 혼란스럽게 할 메모를 적는다.
Violation of the Prevention Act on Love for improper solicitation.
부정청탁금지법 위반입니다.
Violation Get well soon, Wung
위반 빨리 쾌차하세요, Wung
Intentionally posting on social media pretending to be a couple.
의도적으로 커플인 척 SNS에 글을 올리는 행위.
Violation of the Law on Insinuating Relationships on social media.
소셜 미디어에서의 관계 암시에 관한 법률 위반.
Taking a piece of thread off his shoulders.
그의 어깨에서 실 한 조각을 떼어냅니다.
Infringement of ownership regarding one's boyfriend's thread and eye booger.
남친의 실타래와 눈부신 물건에 대한 소유권 침해.
Dongdongju is Wung's favorite.
동동주는 웅이가 가장 좋아하는 것이다.
Violation of the Act on trying to prove that she knows more about Wung,
자신이 Wung에 대해 더 많이 알고 있음을 증명하려는 행위에 대한 법률 위반,
And the Act on the Protection of My Man's Personal Information.
그리고 내 남자의 개인정보 보호에 관한 법률.
Moving to Wung's officetel.
웅 오피스텔로 이사합니다.
What?
무엇?
Going to Wung's house frequently,
Wung의 집에 자주 가죠
Violation of the Special Law on Access Restricted Zones.
접근제한구역 특별법 위반.
Acknowledging all these crimes, I have made a judgment.
나는 이 모든 범죄를 인정하고 판결을 내렸습니다.
Yumi is innocent, Seo Sae Yi is guilty!
유미는 무죄, 서세이는 유죄!
Therefore, Seo Sae Yi can get lost!
그러므로 서세이가 길을 잃을 수도 있다!
Geez. [I love Yumi]
이런. [유미를 사랑해요]
Now do you understand why your actions are wrong?
이제 당신의 행동이 왜 잘못되었는지 이해하셨나요?
If you were Wung's friend, you shouldn't put him in difficult situations as a friend.
당신이 웅의 친구라면 그를 친구로서 어려운 상황에 몰아넣어서는 안 됩니다.
If you sincerely cherished him as a friend. Isn't that so?
진심으로 그를 친구처럼 아꼈다면. 그렇지 않나요?
That's what I would do.
그게 내가 할 일이다.
- If you were really my friend. Yumi, that's enough.
- 당신이 정말 내 친구라면. 유미, 그거면 충분해.
Put yourself in my shoes and think about it.
내 입장이 되어 생각해 보세요.
- Think about how the other person would feel. - Yumi.
- 상대방이 어떻게 느낄지 생각해 보세요. - 유미.
- Would you be happy if you were in my shoes? - Yumi!
- 당신이 내 입장이라면 행복할까요? - 유미!
That's enough.
그것으로 충분합니다.
Stop it already.
이제 그만하세요.
Yumi.
유미.
Yumi come to your senses!
유미 정신 차리세요!
What's wrong? Guys!
무슨 일이야? 얘들아!
Judge! Your judgment was counterproductive.
판사! 당신의 판단은 역효과를 냈습니다.
Yumi can't say anything!
유미는 아무 말도 할 수 없어!
It's because Yumi can only choose to lose now.
이제 유미는 지는 선택밖에 할 수 없기 때문이다.
What?
무엇?
Yumi doesn't intend on breaking up with Wung at all.
유미는 웅과 헤어질 생각이 전혀 없다.
If she doesn't have any intention of breaking up, then it doesn't matter how much they fight,
그녀가 헤어질 생각이 없다면 아무리 싸워도 상관없습니다.
ultimately, she'll have no choice but to give in.
결국 그녀는 포기할 수밖에 없을 것입니다.
Show me the card you have.
가지고 있는 카드를 보여주세요.
Surrendering surrender no matter what
항복 무슨 일이 있어도 항복해
The remaining card is Surrender isn't it?
남은 카드는 항복이겠죠?
- Yes. - Here.
- 예. - 여기.
Throw that card away and take this.
그 카드를 버리고 이것을 가져가세요.
This is-
이건-
The Breakup card. It's a card that should always be kept with you when you're in a relationship.
이별 카드. 연애를 할 때 항상 가지고 다녀야 할 카드입니다.
We've never had this before.
우리는 전에 이런 적이 없었습니다.
Without this, Yumi can't do what she wants.
이것이 없으면 유미는 자신이 원하는 것을 할 수 없습니다.
From now on, Yumi will use the Breakup card.
이제부터 유미는 이별카드를 사용하게 됩니다.
Breakup 'Let's break up'
이별 '헤어지자'
Just by obtaining the Breakup card,
이별 카드를 얻는 것만으로도
Yumi will be able to do whatever she wants now.
이제 유미는 자신이 원하는 것은 무엇이든 할 수 있을 것입니다.
Yumi's Priorities: First Place Gu Wung Second Place Yumi Third Place Mom
Yumi의 우선순위: 1위 Gu Wung 2위 유미 3위 엄마
First Place Yumi (1△) Second Place Gu Wung (1 ▽)
1위 유미(1Δ) 2위 Gu Wung (1 ▽)
Yumi, are you listening?
유미야, 듣고 있어?
Wung.
웅.
No matter what you think of me, I have to say this.
당신이 나를 어떻게 생각하든 나는 이것을 말해야 합니다.
You may not see it in your eyes but the way I see it, that person
눈에는 안 보이겠지만 내가 보기엔 그 사람
is not a good colleague or friend who's worth defending.
방어할 가치가 있는 좋은 동료나 친구가 아닙니다.
Don't keep someone like that by your side, Wung.
그런 사람을 옆에 두지 마세요, 웡.
You're a good person.
당신은 좋은 사람이에요.
Yumi.
유미.
Wung, every time you find someone you care about,
Wung, 당신이 아끼는 사람을 찾을 때마다
your friend will act out again as she is now.
당신의 친구는 지금처럼 다시 행동할 것입니다.
Whoever you meet, that is.
누구를 만나든 그렇습니다.
I'm leaving.
나는 떠난다.
I don't have the power to push aside Seo Sae Yi.
나에겐 서세이를 밀어낼 힘이 없다.
I also can't control Wung the way I want.
나 또한 내가 원하는 대로 Wung을 통제할 수 없다.
But it's my choice to not see him if I don't want to, or to keep seeing him if I want to.
하지만 내가 원하지 않으면 그 사람을 보지 않고, 보고 싶으면 계속 만나는 것은 나의 선택입니다.
Of course, that would be the same for Wung.
물론 그건 웅도 마찬가지일 것이다.
New post
새 게시물
Episode 26 Aigoo.
26화 아이구.
Today I'm going to introduce what I do in a day.
오늘은 제가 하루에 하는 일을 소개하겠습니다.
Wake up!
깨우다!
So noisy! The alarm sound!
너무 시끄러워요! 알람 소리!
Gosh!
이런!
Why am I the only one who hears that noise?
왜 저만 그 소리가 들리나요?
Wake up!
깨우다!
♫ With only dust flying under the light bulb ♫
♫ 전구 아래에는 먼지만 날리며 ♫
My busy day starts with Yumi turning off the alarm.
나의 바쁜 하루는 유미가 알람을 끄는 것부터 시작된다.
♫ When rain pours ♫
♫ 비가 쏟아지면 ♫
♫ without respite. Once more ♫
♫ 쉬지 않고. 한 번 더 ♫
In the morning, there's a lot to do.
아침에는 할 일이 많습니다.
Hey, wake up! Guys, wake up!
이봐, 일어나! 얘들아, 일어나!
We have to go to work.
우리는 일하러 가야 해요.
Hey! What do you think you're doing, you crazy jerk!
여기요! 지금 무슨 짓을 하고 있는 것 같냐, 이 미친놈아!
So cold!
너무 추워요!
Good morning!
좋은 아침이에요!
It's also my job to wake up Fashion cell and Face Wash cell.
패션셀과 세안셀을 깨우는 것도 나의 일이다.
♫ A holiday where through the leaves there is a small boat. ♫
♫ 나뭇잎 사이로 작은 배가 있는 휴일. ♫
What should I wear?
무엇을 입어야 하나요?
I wore this yesterday.
어제 이걸 입었어요.
I wore that all last week.
지난주 내내 그걸 입었어요.
There's nothing to wear. Nothing. Kim Yumi needs to buy clothes.
입을 것이 없습니다. 아무것도 아님. 김유미는 옷을 사야 해요.
How on earth am I supposed to—
도대체 내가 어떻게—
Choose quickly! We don't have time!
빨리 선택하세요! 시간이 없어요!
Let's just wear that.
그냥 그거 입자.
- Good morning! - Yi Da, good morning!
- 좋은 아침이에요! - 이다, 좋은 아침이에요!
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Thank you!
감사합니다!
When Yumi comes to work, I usually roll the millstone.
유미가 출근하면 주로 맷돌을 굴립니다.
Maybe it's because the weather's nice but there are no cells helping out today.
날씨가 좋아서인지 오늘은 도와줄 세포가 없네요.
The weather's so nice today.
오늘 날씨가 너무 좋네요.
You're supposed to go on picnics on days like this, right?
이런 날에는 소풍을 가야 하는 거겠죠?
Right.
오른쪽.
The only one who helps me is Stingy cell.
나를 도와주는 유일한 사람은 Stingy Cell뿐입니다.
Thanks, Stingy.
고마워요, 스팅지.
I want to make Yumi rich.
나는 유미를 부자로 만들고 싶다.
Huh?
뭐?
You're going to make her rich by saving her salary?
그녀의 월급을 아껴서 그녀를 부자로 만들 건가요?
Yes!
예!
Fortunately, there is also a break time.
다행히 쉬는 시간도 있어요.
Hi guys! What should we eat for lunch?
안녕 얘들 아! 우리 점심으로 무엇을 먹어야 할까요?
♫ the more the night slips away ♫
♫ 밤이 점점 멀어질수록 ♫
So good. It tastes so good.
너무 좋아요. 맛이 너무 좋아요.
Eonni, look at the part time worker.
언니야, 알바하는 사람 좀 봐.
It's him, the flower boy*. (Refers to handsome men)
바로 그 꽃미남*입니다. (잘생긴 남자를 가리킨다)
It's so good, isn't it?
정말 좋은데요, 그렇죠?
From 11:30 a.m. to 1 p.m. we get to rest thanks to Hunger.
오전 11시 30분부터 오후 1시까지. Hunger 덕분에 쉴 수 있어요.
I'm so happy.
정말 기뻐요.
Eonni, what happened?
언니, 무슨 일 있었나요?
- What? - You fought with your boyfriend last week.
- 무엇? - 지난주에 남자친구와 싸웠어요.
♫It's a holiday where through the leaves there was a small boat and me.  ♫
♫나뭇잎 사이로 작은 배와 내가 있었던 휴일이다.  ♫
What? She's asking a sensitive question again.
무엇? 또 민감한 질문을 하더군요.
Wait! I'll answer that!
기다리다! 나는 그것에 대답할 것이다!
I also have to go during important conversations.
중요한 대화가 있을 때도 가야 해요.
What do you mean fight? Who?
싸운다는 게 무슨 말이에요? WHO?
It was so obvious. What happened? Did you two make up?
너무나 분명했습니다. 무슨 일이에요? 둘이 화해했어요?
No.
아니요.
- Your coffee is ready. - What? You broke up?
- 커피가 준비되었습니다. - 무엇? 헤어졌어?
What are you two talking about?
둘이 무슨 얘기하는 거야?
Nope. We didn't fight.
아니요. 우리는 싸우지 않았습니다.
What's she saying?
그 사람이 무슨 말을 하는 거야?
They must have made up.
그들은 화해했을 것입니다.
Let's raise it a little to the right.
오른쪽으로 조금 올려보겠습니다.
Yeah, yeah.
응, 응.
That's good, that's good.
좋아요, 좋아요.
-Good? -Yeah.
-좋은? -응.
Remembering the important memories in Yumi's life is a part of my job.
유미의 인생에서 중요한 추억을 기억하는 것은 내 일의 일부이다.
It's so beautiful.
너무 아름다워요.
As the sun sets, Sensitivity wakes up from her sleep.
해가 지면서 감성은 잠에서 깨어난다.
Someday I will go to Africa.
언젠가 나는 아프리카에 갈 것이다.
Africa!
아프리카!
We'll run through the grasslands with a herd of buffalo and greet the magnificent sunset, right?
버팔로 떼와 함께 초원을 달리며 멋진 일몰을 맞이하게 되겠죠?
When Sensitivity wakes up, we can consider the millstone work for the day is over.
감성이 깨어나면 하루의 맷돌작업이 끝났다고 볼 수 있다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
Goodbye!
안녕히 가세요!
♫ Rising higher than my breath ♫
♫ 내 숨결보다 높이 솟아오른다 ♫
What time do you finish work today?
오늘 일 몇시에 끝나요?
Should I come get you?
내가 당신을 데리러 와야 할까요?
I try my best to stay out of dating-related issues.
나는 데이트 관련 문제를 피하려고 최선을 다합니다.
♫ For us ♫
♫ 우리를 위해 ♫
How about we respond like this? I was thinking...
우리는 이렇게 대답하는 것이 어떨까요? 내 생각엔...
Because that is Love's job.
그게 사랑의 일이니까.
Love, can you add a P.S.?
자기야, 추신을 추가해 주실 수 있나요?
What?
무엇?
Wung, do you know what underwear I wore today?
웅아, 내가 오늘 어떤 속옷을 입었는지 알아?
Hey Naughty! Stop it right there!
안녕 버릇없어! 당장 그만둬!
But because of Naughty, I can't fully rest.
하지만 Naughty 때문에 완전히 쉴 수가 없어요.
When it gets late, there is still the hardest thing to do.
늦어도 여전히 가장 어려운 일이 있습니다.
♫ I feel you intensifying ♫
♫ 당신이 점점 더 격렬해지는 걸 느껴요 ♫
♫ Sweet cologne  ♫
♫ 달콤한 향수 ♫
♫ Truth be told ♫
♫ 진실을 말해주세요 ♫
I'm hungry! Let's eat a late-night snack!
배고파요! 야식을 먹자!
I said I'm hungry! ♫ Hunger! Hunger! ♫
나는 배고프다고 말했다! ♫ 배고픔! 굶주림! ♫
- I want dumplings and chocolate! - Hunger, Hunger!
- 만두와 초콜릿을 원해요! - 배고파, 배고파!
Chicken feet!
닭발!
Over here! Bring me back up!
여기요! 날 다시 일으켜줘!
- Fried chicken! - Hunger!
- 후라이드 치킨! - 배고프다!
Resist. Resist.
저항하다. 저항하다.
I need to resist.
저항해야 해요.
After Hunger calms down, the writer cell comes to help.
배고픔이 진정되면 작가 세포가 도움을 주러 옵니다.
yumiii_0109
yumiii_0109
Since Yumi's writer cell was revived, she started to write again.
유미의 작가세포가 부활하면서 다시 글을 쓰기 시작했다.
Writer, it's not "I go"
작가님, "가겠습니다"가 아닙니다
it's "I'll go" (spelling error)
"가겠습니다" 입니다 (철자 오류)
"I'll go"
"가겠습니다"
It's not that "personality was wrong", but it'd be better to say "personality changed"
"성격이 틀렸다"는 게 아니라 "성격이 바뀌었다"고 말하는 게 낫겠다
Just something to note. Work hard!
참고할 점이 있습니다. 열심히 일하세요!
Because of him I can't get into the right emotion!
그 사람 때문에 나는 올바른 감정을 느낄 수 없습니다!
Post
게시
Successfully posted
성공적으로 게시되었습니다
♫ Nightfalling ♫
♫ 해질녘 ♫
♫ Because you are within my two eyes ♫
♫ 당신은 내 두 눈 안에 있기 때문이죠 ♫
It's all over now.
이제 다 끝났습니다.
♫ I'm hiding the especially red cheeks ♫
♫ 유난히 붉은 볼을 숨기고 있어요 ♫
Good job, Reason. I'll put her to sleep now.
잘했어요, 이유. 이제 그녀를 재울게요.
Thanks, do a good job!
고마워요, 잘 지내세요!
♫ You and I ♫
♫ 당신과 나 ♫
♪ Rockabye baby, on the tree top ♪ ♫ are headed toward the same place♫
♪ Rockabye 자기야, 나무 꼭대기에 ♪ ♫ 같은 곳을 향해 가고 있어요♫
♫ When this night passes  ♫
♫ 이 밤이 지나면 ♫
♫ Oh we'll know ♫
♫ 아, 우리가 알게 될 거야 ♫
It's not just me having a hard time like this.
나만 이렇게 힘든 게 아니다.
I'm sure all of the other reason cells in this world have busy days like this.
이 세상의 모든 세포들이 이렇게 바쁜 나날을 보내는 이유는 분명 있을 것입니다.
Reason cells, stay strong.
이유세포여, 힘내세요.
Reason, what are you doing?
이유야, 뭐 하는 거야?
Look at the sky! Why is the color like that?
하늘을 봐! 색깔이 왜 저럴까요?
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I've never seen a sky like that.
나는 그런 하늘을 본 적이 없습니다.
What is going on with Wung's emotions, that the sky looks like this?
하늘이 이렇게 보이는 웅의 감정은 어떻게 된 걸까요?
Hey Louis. Coffee.
안녕 루이스. 커피.
What are you so worried about?
뭘 그렇게 걱정해요?
Deciding to do it ourselves without Sae Yi, there is no end to this. No end.
세이 없이 스스로 하기로 결정하면 끝이 없다. 끝이 없습니다.
I mean, we haven't been able to go home for days. What is this?
내 말은, 우리는 며칠 동안 집에 갈 수 없었다는 거예요. 이게 뭔가요?
Sae Yi worked so fast. I didn't know her absence would feel this big.
세이는 정말 빨리 일했어요. 그녀의 부재가 이렇게 크게 느껴질 줄은 몰랐다.
We've put an announcement, so I'm sure we'll get contacted soon.
공지를 올려놨으니 곧 연락이 올 거라 믿습니다.
I talked to Sae Yi earlier,
아까 세이랑 얘기했는데,
she decided to go into the company that scouted her.
그녀는 자신을 스카우트한 회사에 들어가기로 결정했습니다.
She seemed to be really angry at you.
그녀는 당신에게 정말 화가 난 것 같았습니다.
- Really? - So why did you two fight so much?
- 정말? - 그럼 왜 둘이 그렇게 많이 싸웠나요?
It's only been a day or two since you two fought.
너희 둘이 싸운 지 하루 이틀밖에 안 됐어.
Are you not going to see her ever again? Not even once?
그녀를 다시는 볼 수 없나요? 한 번도 아니지?
Wung, we all worked together for so long. You don't feel sad at all?
웅, 우리 모두 오랫동안 함께 일했어요. 전혀 슬프지 않나요?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
What do you mean you're not sure?
확실하지 않다은 무슨 뜻인가요?
I don't really know.
나는 정말로 모른다.
Wung's sky isn't in the book?
Wung의 하늘은 책에 없나요?
Let's see. Regular sky is yellow, that's not it.
어디 보자. 보통 하늘은 노란색인데, 그게 아니다.
Isn't it the sad sky?
슬픈 하늘이 아닌가?
No no, look at it carefully. The color is different.
아니 아니, 잘 살펴보세요. 색상이 다릅니다.
It's not the sad sky.
슬픈 하늘이 아니다.
That's true. Illustrated Book of Wung's Skies
그것은 사실이다. 웅의 하늘 그림책
Oh wait! Could that be a mix of moods?
아 잠깐! 기분이 혼합된 것이 아닐까요?
Look! When he's sorry, it's green. When he's mad, its a red sky.
바라보다! 그가 미안할 때는 녹색입니다. 화가 나면 하늘이 붉어진다.
When he is feeling regret, it's purple.
후회할 때는 보라색이에요.
If you add all of those colors, it becomes this poop color!
그 색들을 다 더하면 이런 똥색이 됩니다!
So he's sorry, mad, and regretful?
그럼 미안하고 화나고 후회하는 걸까요?
Wow. This is not good.
우와. 이것은 좋지 않습니다.
I feel sorry because it's my fault,
내 잘못이라 미안해
and feel mad about why she ended it this way,
그녀가 왜 이런 식으로 끝냈는지 화가 났어요
and feel regretful because Sae Yi isn't here anymore. I guess it's like that.
세이가 더 이상 없어서 아쉬워요. 그런 것 같아요.
Couldn't you meet her and make up?
그 사람을 만나서 화해할 수는 없었나요?
No. I don't think that's right.
아뇨. 내 생각엔 그게 옳지 않은 것 같아요.
- Why? - It's something that was brewing for some time.
- 왜? - 한동안 양조 중이던 일입니다.
It was bound to happen some day.
언젠가는 일어날 일이었습니다.
I'll tell you honestly.
솔직하게 말씀드리겠습니다.
It's not that I didn't know.
몰랐던 건 아닙니다.
I was just pretending not to know.
그냥 모른 척 했을 뿐입니다.
What?
무엇?
How you felt about me all this time.
그동안 나에 대해 어떻게 느꼈는지.
Too precious to give to anyone else, but too much to have for yourself. That's how you've been feeling.
다른 사람에게 주기에는 너무 소중하지만 자신을 위해서는 너무 많은 것입니다. 당신도 그렇게 느꼈어요.
I've known this, all along.
나는 이것을 줄곧 알고 있었습니다.
- Wung ... - I pretended not to know,
- 웅... - 모르는 척 했어요
because it wasn't that important to me. But I don't think I can do that anymore.
왜냐하면 그것은 나에게 그다지 중요하지 않았기 때문입니다. 하지만 더 이상 그렇게 할 수 없을 것 같아요.
Don't think of me as your backup, Sae Yi.
나를 당신의 백업으로 생각하지 마세요, Sae Yi.
There is no chance at all of that happening.
그런 일이 일어날 가능성은 전혀 없습니다.
You have to promise me that ... So that I can be able to work with you again.
나한테 약속해야 해... 내가 다시 당신과 함께 일할 수 있도록요.
Hey. Gu Wung. You think you can make whatever judgments you want,
여기요. 구웅. 당신은 당신이 원하는 어떤 판단도 내릴 수 있다고 생각해요,
come to whatever conclusions you want, and reject me however you want?
당신이 원하는 대로 결론을 내리고, 당신이 원하는 대로 나를 거부하시겠습니까?
- I can't believe this. - I'm not the same Gu Wung from college, Sae Yi.
- 믿을 수가 없어요. - 저는 예전의 대학생 구웅이 아닙니다, 세이.
Someone who did whatever you wanted because he was immature.
철없어서 하고 싶은 대로 다 해 준 사람.
So?
그래서?
- What? - Are you going to marry Kim Yumi?
- 무엇? - 김유미와 결혼할 건가요?
You made a promise to each other, huh?
서로 약속했잖아요?
It hasn't been that long since you two started dating.
두 사람이 연애를 시작한지는 그리 오래되지 않았습니다.
And me? It's been over ten years for us.
그리고 나는요? 우리에게는 벌써 10년이 넘었습니다.
It's been over ten years. With the same goals, until now.
벌써 10년이 넘었습니다. 같은 목표를 가지고 지금까지.
Sae Yi, this has nothing to do with Yumi.
세이 씨, 이건 유미 씨와는 아무 관련이 없어요.
This is about the relationship between you and me.
이것은 당신과 나의 관계에 관한 것입니다.
Whether we are even truly friends. Or if we mistakenly ended up here.
우리가 진정한 친구인지도요. 아니면 우리가 실수로 여기까지 왔다면요.
I'm sure she'll do well. She's really talented.
나는 그녀가 잘 할 것이라고 확신합니다. 그녀는 정말 재능이 있어요.
I really don't know.
나는 정말로 모른다.
Everything will be fine over time. Let's get to work, okay?
시간이 지나면 모든 것이 괜찮아질 것입니다. 일하러 가자, 응?
It's ... it's not okay.
그건... 안 돼요.
Snow. It's going to be hard when I get off work.
눈. 퇴근하면 힘들겠다.
Assistant Manager Yumi.
유미 대리.
Kim Yumi!
김유미!
Here.
여기.
Take a coffee with you.
당신과 함께 커피를 가져 가라.
All right.
괜찮은.
But, did you call me Kim Yumi just now?
그런데 방금 김유미라고 부르셨나요?
I'm sorry, it seemed like you didn't hear me when I called.
미안해요. 제가 전화했을 때 제 말을 듣지 못한 것 같았어요.
What would you like?
무엇을 원하시나요?
Then, a hot latte...
그럼 따뜻한 라떼 한잔...
One hot latte please.
따뜻한 라떼 하나 주세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You don't seem to be working out these days.
요즘 운동을 안 하시는 것 같더라고요.
I stopped working out after the race.
나는 경주가 끝난 후 운동을 중단했습니다.
The race is over already?
경주는 이미 끝났나요?
Yes, two weeks ago.
네, 2주 전이에요.
Which place did you get?
어느 곳에서 구하셨나요?
What matters is that I participated.
중요한 것은 내가 참여했다는 것이다.
Yes.
예.
I'll guess on my own.
제가 직접 추측해 보겠습니다.
Your latte is ready.
라떼가 준비되었습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Here.
여기.
Isn't the snow ...
눈이 내리지 않나요...
- so nice? - It makes me worried about getting home.
- 정말 좋은데? - 집에 가는 게 걱정돼요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I am not romantic.
나는 낭만적이지 않습니다.
I don't really like winter to begin with.
저는 원래 겨울을 별로 안 좋아해요.
It's cold, and it snows.
춥고 눈이 옵니다.
- Even Christmas? - Christmas?
- 크리스마스에도요? - 크리스마스?
What are you doing for Christmas?
크리스마스에 뭐해요?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
I don't think I'll know until then, because my boyfriend is busy.
남자친구가 바쁘기 때문에 그때까지는 알 수 없을 것 같아요.
Me too. Making plans is meaningless because of my girlfriend's schedule.
저도요. 여자친구의 스케줄 때문에 계획을 세우는 것이 의미가 없습니다.
Oh, by the way, I made the tartar sauce you taught me back then.
아 그런데 그때 가르쳐주신 타르타르 소스는 제가 만들었어요.
Really?
정말?
It's different from buying one, it tasted better.
하나 사먹는 것과는 달라서 더 맛있더라구요.
Right? I developed that.
오른쪽? 나는 그것을 개발했습니다.
I'm good with sauces.
저는 소스를 잘 먹거든요.
They say when you are good at making sauces, you are a master of cooking.
소스를 잘 만들면 요리의 달인이라고 하잖아요.
I'm not, I just have some interest.
난 아니고 그냥 관심이 좀 있는 것 뿐이에요.
I like looking for good restaurants.
나는 좋은 레스토랑을 찾는 것을 좋아합니다.
You can go ahead, I have to buy something first.
가세요. 먼저 뭔가를 사야 해요.
Yes.
예.
- Ah, right. - Yes?
- 아, 그렇죠. - 예?
I wanted to ask you something...
뭔가 물어보고 싶었는데...
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I'll ask you later.
나중에 물어볼게요.
Yumi!
유미!
Wung!
웅!
Did you wait for long?
오래 기다리셨나요?
No, but it's really cold now.
아니, 그런데 지금은 정말 추워요.
My hands are freezing.
내 손이 얼고있다.
Your hands are freezing?
손이 얼고 있나요?
If your hands are freezing...
손이 얼면...
Hey, I'm fine. There are so many people, what are you doing?
안녕, 난 괜찮아. 사람이 이렇게 많은데 뭐하세요?
Docking right hand, left hand.
도킹 오른손, 왼손.
Success.
성공.
Now, there's no way for the warmth to escape.
이제 더위가 빠져나갈 방법이 없습니다.
It's the best.
최고입니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Tell me if your feet are cold, I'll do your feet too.
발이 추우면 말씀해주세요. 발도 닦아드릴께요.
How would you do the feet?
발은 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
Wung, you can have all this.
웡, 당신은 이 모든 것을 가질 수 있어요.
I am full.
나는 배불러요.
But, today you...
하지만 오늘 당신은...
What?
무엇?
There's no way.
방법이 없습니다.
What? What?
무엇? 무엇?
You're pretty.
당신은 예쁘다.
You scared me.
당신은 나를 겁주었어요.
Make that compliment more ticklish*. (In a more obvious or embarrassing manner)
칭찬을 더욱 간지럽게 만드세요*. (더 명백하거나 당황스러운 방식으로)
- Ticklish? - Yes.
- 간지러워요? - 예.
Pretty.
예쁜.
Not this kind of tickling.
이런 간지러움이 아닙니다.
That tickles!
간지러워요!
So noisy!
너무 시끄러워요!
Look. It's starting now.
바라보다. 이제 시작이에요.
How was the movie?
영화는 어땠나요?
It was fun, why are the reviews so bad?
재밌었는데 평가가 왜이렇게 안좋나요?
I liked it too. If you have finished drinking, give it to me.
나도 그것을 좋아했다. 다 마셨다면 나에게 주세요.
No.
아니요.
I'll throw it for you, give it to me.
내가 당신을 위해 던질 테니 나에게주세요.
No it's okay, there is still some left.
아냐 괜찮아 아직 좀 남았어
There is? Then give me some.
있어요? 그럼 좀 주세요.
I've been wanting to try the milk tea.
밀크티를 먹어보고 싶었는데
Wow.
우와.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Is it good?
좋은가요?
It's really good. This is how it should taste.
정말 좋아요. 이런 맛이 나야 합니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
You should have told me earlier.
좀 더 일찍 말했어야 했는데.
Ah, I guess I like milk tea.
아, 아무래도 밀크티를 좋아하는 것 같아요.
After the end of the year, Wung and I will have been dating for two years.
연말이 지나면 Wung과 저는 2년 동안 데이트를 하게 됩니다.
At this point, the excitement decreased, but there was something else instead.
이때 설렘은 줄어들었지만 대신 뭔가가 있었다.
We have to wait at least ten minutes.
우리는 적어도 10분은 기다려야 합니다.
Shall we sit down a bit? Bus Route Map
우리 좀 앉아볼까? 버스 노선도
Wait.
기다리다.
I'm good. You don't have to do all that.
난 괜찮아. 그 모든 것을 할 필요는 없습니다.
You also sit.
당신도 앉아 있습니다.
Wow.
우와.
It's hard to explain exactly what that is.
그것이 정확히 무엇인지 설명하기는 어렵습니다.
I said sit.
나는 앉으라고 말했다.
♫ What's changed is the person I love. ♫
♫ 변한 것은 내가 사랑하는 사람이다. ♫
But at that moment, you say "Aigoo."
그런데 그 순간 "아이구"라고 하더군요.
Are you having fun?
재미있나요?
Yes, today was also fun.
응, 오늘도 즐거웠어.
If you're having fun, then I'm having fun too.
당신이 즐거우면 나도 즐거우니까요.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
#writingstagram #scribbling #dailylife
#글스타그램 #낙서 #일상
Share post
게시물 공유
♫ That someone has become a precious ♫
♫ 누군가가 소중한 사람이 되었다는 것 ♫
♫ person to me makes me  ♫
♫ 사람이 나를 만든다 ♫
♫ love the time I spend with her. ♫
♫ 그녀와 함께 보내는 시간이 정말 좋아요. ♫
Yes, Wung. Did you get home?
응, 웅. 집에 도착했어요?
No, I haven't slept yet.
아니요, 아직 잠을 못 잤어요.
I was writing.
나는 글을 쓰고 있었다.
Our story.
우리의 이야기.
There's something like that.
그런 게 있어요.
You can see later. It's embarrassing.
나중에 볼 수 있습니다. 당황스럽다.
But, what took you so long to get home?
그런데 집에 오는 데 왜 그렇게 오래 걸렸나요?
It's snowing?
눈이 오나요?
It's snowing a lot.
눈이 많이 내리고 있어요.
How do I go to work tomorrow?
내일 회사에 어떻게 가나요?
But it's still pretty.
하지만 여전히 예쁘네요.
It really feels like winter.
정말 겨울이 느껴지네요.
When it snows like this, you have to build a snowman or have a snowball fight.
이렇게 눈이 오면 눈사람을 만들거나 눈싸움을 해야 합니다.
I did that a lot when I was a kid.
어렸을 때 그런 짓을 많이 했어요.
Be the first to Like.
가장 먼저 좋아요를 눌러보세요.
1 Like
좋아요 1개
♫ In so many thoughts we ♫
♫ 우리는 수많은 생각 속에서 ♫
♫ meet again on another day ♫
♫ 다른 날에 다시 만나요 ♫
♫ Let's put behind us our weary hearts ♫
♫ 지친 마음을 뒤로합시다 ♫
♫ and think about someone ♫
♫ 그리고 누군가에 대해 생각해 보세요 ♫
♫ Because in matters which had nothing to do with me ♫
♫ 왜냐면 나와 상관없는 일이니까 ♫
♫ I uselessly took an interest ♫
♫ 쓸데없이 관심을 가졌어 ♫
Yumi's Cells
유미의 세포
You saw my post?
내 글 봤어?
Yes, I stumbled across it through an employee's account.
네, 직원 계정을 통해 우연히 발견했습니다.
How should I put this? It's hard to explain but they seem just like you.
이건 어떻게 넣어야 하나요? 설명하기 어렵지만 그들은 당신과 꼭 닮은 것 같습니다.
What do you mean by just like me?
나랑 똑같다은 무슨 뜻인가요?
Think about it carefully, I highly recommend it
잘 생각해 보세요. 적극 추천합니다
The department head suddenly suggested it. What do you think?
부서장이 갑자기 제안을 하더군요. 어떻게 생각하나요?
- 30 minutes? - It will take me thirty minutes because I'm putting effort into it.
- 30분? - 노력하고 있으니까 30분 정도 걸릴 거예요.
Usually it wouldn't take more than ten minutes.
보통 10분도 채 걸리지 않습니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
You said it just has to be to three or four lines. I'll try it. I think I can do it.
3~4줄만 하면 된다고 하더군요. 나는 그것을 시도할 것이다. 나는 그것을 할 수 있다고 생각합니다.
I can't even write three or four lines? That doesn't make sense.
세 줄, 네 줄도 못 쓰나요? 그건 말이 안 돼요.
It's only three or four lines.
고작 3~4줄이면 됩니다.
I must be crazy.
나는 미친 게 분명하다.
♫ When that happens will you say to me "you did well" and "good job"? ♫
♫ 그런 일이 생기면 나한테 "잘했어", "수고했어"라고 말해줄 건가요? ♫